<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Eric's Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-18T14:44:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://EricNY.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Abt]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[End Week 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/end-week-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/end-week-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week we had our longest project yet. We built a crowdsourcing app similar to Kickstarter. It was very involved and at times things got frustrating but I worked with two great partners in Kyle and Julian. I feel there are times when it makes sense to work alone but it absolutely makes sense to work with others at other times, especially for large projects! We worked on breaking the whole app down into smaller tasks and assigning them out. It&rsquo;s important to get along with and respect your teammates and these guys were great! There were some times I felt I was struggling to keep up but it kept me motivated to learn more and I hope they enjoyed working with me as well.</p>

<p>Our app allows users to log in and create a profile. Then they can either start their own fundraising campaign and/or donate to someone elses campaign. I think we will win the prize for sweetest layout! I was able to put a status bar on the top of the campaign page that fills up as people donate and I put in a picture carousel that scrolls through pictures that a campaign creator uploads. Julian is working on making the entire background play a video behind all the content, looked really good when he was testing it &ndash; lets see if we can incorporate it in time!</p>

<p>I wanted to add a comment section but ran out of time. But then again, maybe I shouldn&rsquo;t per our class discussion on app development best practices. Nimit and David recommended we read a book called Getting Real by 37 Signals which is the company that developed Rails. In it there is an reference to the &ldquo;less is more&rdquo; philosophy and we should not try to put too much in an app just because we can. Focusing on the &ldquo;must haves&rdquo; and omitting the &ldquo;don&rsquo;t needs&rdquo; will lead to a more elegant design. Although, while we are just learning, I admit it&rsquo;s fun to add in cool things like a video background, comment section, a robot monkey that can do your taxes, etc&hellip;</p>

<p>Overall I am starting to see the power of the Rails framework and I like how we took the time for an &ldquo;under the hood&rdquo; approach to understanding it. I hope to go through Michael Hartl&rsquo;s tutorial on it again soon and reinforce what I&rsquo;ve been doing.</p>

<p>-E</p>

<p>P.S. We have not pushed our crowdsourcing app to the internet yet but will post a link when we do. I was pushing to name it FullTilt (a cross between Fullstack Academy and CrowdTilt) but we settled on Crowdcontrol.</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;End Week 5&rdquo;
date: 2013-10-18 10:29
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crowdcontrol Is Live]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/crowdcontrol-is-live/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/crowdcontrol-is-live</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CrowdControl is live!</p>

<p>Check it out here: <a href="http://crowd-control.herokuapp.com/">http://crowd-control.herokuapp.com/</a></p>

<p>Thanks for hanging in there. Couple things&hellip;
1. password must be 8 characters
2. to get the picture carousel working you have to click on an arrow once.
3. Im not sure the video background is necessary but dammit its cool!
4. If you just want to see the payment functionality obviously we dont want you to enter your real cc info. You can just input 4242424242&hellip;..</p>

<p>Not bad for a couple of newbies hacking away for 3 days:)</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;crowdcontrol is live&rdquo;
date: 2013-10-18 14:19
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[1 Slash 3 Of The Way There]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/1-slash-3-of-the-way-there/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/1-slash-3-of-the-way-there</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s true. Time sure flies when you are having fun. Today marks the end of the fourth week so that means we have 2/3 rds of the course to go. I still have a lot to learn but I feel we have come a long way since day 1. But then I suppose the learning will never stop so I should take time and appreciate what we&rsquo;ve done so far.</p>

<p>This week we started building actual rails apps, here is my first one: (<a href="http://shrouded-meadow-3132.herokuapp.com/rooms/1">http://shrouded-meadow-3132.herokuapp.com/rooms/1</a>). All the pieces we have been learning are coming together and I need more practice but it is pretty satisfying to see something I do actually work. OK, there are some bugs but I know how to fix them and maybe I&rsquo;ll go back to this one in my spare time. But for now we got to keep going as the class moves pretty fast!</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;1/3 of the way there :(&rdquo;
date: 2013-10-11 09:57
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/week-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/week-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK. Week 3 has come and gone and things are getting intense. We started taking the different pieces we have been learning and putting them together. The projects are getting more difficult but I am starting to see the bigger picture of what is involved with web development and its very exciting.</p>

<p>This week we used ActiveRecord and SQL to access more IMDB data. We had to write code for an empty model.</p>

<p>We also used Sinatra to build our first fully functioning web app. We call it Stackworld where a user can add a personal profile and create their own world where different rooms can link to eachother and they can navigate through the world.</p>

<p>Lastly, we brushed up on regular expressions and we just got our new exciting which I feel will be difficult but its a really cool thing to know. We will be building a web crawler which will allow us to scrape websites for data and create a graph using that data. Apparently this is some serious technology so we all made a pact to use our new powers for good instead of evil:)</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;Week 3&rdquo;
date: 2013-10-04 09:39
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello all,</p>

<p>We are finishing up week 2 here at Fullstack Academy and I couldnt be happier! This week we wrote an AI program that plays Blackjack, we worked on getting a basic working knowledge of SQL, and we learned how to use Ruby code to connect to and query an SQLite database of IMDB data.</p>

<p>For the Blackjack program it was more TDD as we partnered up with another class member. The SQL exercises started very basic but the last few and the extra credit got a little hairy. Now I know just how complex SQL queries can become but its fun to puzzle the pieces together. Using Ruby to connect to a database was very interesting as well. It really helped for me to start putting the pieces together of the various disciplines involved in web development.</p>

<p>This weekend I hope to review various rails tutorials as well as my mailer program which is what I use to send my weekly updates to my blog subscribers. I dont have it working exactly as it should just yet.</p>

<p>Until next time!!</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;Week 2 update&rdquo;
date: 2013-09-27 09:50
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[End Of Week 1 A Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/end-of-week-1-a-retrospective/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/end-of-week-1-a-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are wrapping up week one here at Fullstack and I think we covered a good amount of work but I feel like it will only get more intense from here. Something tells me there will be many evenings where I dont get home until verrry late:)</p>

<p>The most interesting thing we did this week was probably our mailer assignment from yesterday. We got to use CSV files, .erb files, Ruby and HTML and we had to make them all work together. The final result was to be able to send an email or text to a list of friends notifying them of our latest blog entry.</p>

<p>Something I struggle with is understanding what is going on with the code we are writing, specifically for this mailer assignment. While it is very interesting stuff and the code I wrote works I feel I do not have a deep understanding of what we just did. I want to review this project when I get the chance.</p>

<p>I like the format of the class. David and Nimit give us enough lecture time so we cover various concepts but we also have plenty of time to actually get down to business and work through coding challenges ourselves.</p>

<p>Pair programming is new to me but I can see the benefits. Sometimes it was unclear which one of us was in the driver&rsquo;s seat as we talked through problems but it definitely helps to have a sounding board for your ideas as we are working through a challenge together.</p>

<p>This weekend I plan on reviewing what we did in class this week as well as some of the pre-work.</p>

<p>-Eric</p>

<h2>date: 2013-09-20 09:</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;End of Week 1: A Retrospective&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://EricNY.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK first post here and first time using Markdown.</p>

<h1>Here is a header</h1>

<p>And this is an <em>italicized sequence of words</em>
&hellip;here is <strong>bold</strong></p>

<p>How about a list?
1. Breakfast
2. Lunch
3. Dinner
..<em> ramen
..</em> veggies
..* fish</p>

<hr />

<p>layout: post
title: &ldquo;First Post&rdquo;
date: 2013-09-17 11:11
comments: true</p>

<h2>categories:</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
